《生活大爆炸》前情回顾
Previously on The Big Bang Theory...
请大家听我说几句
Can I have your attention, please?
今晚我们齐聚一堂是因为
We're all here tonight
我们没有另一半相陪
because we have no one to be with.
我们不能再以是否有恋爱对象
We've got to stop defining our self-worth
来定义我们的自我价值
by whether or not we're in a relationship.
我们是一个联盟
We are a community,
只要我们团结在一起
and as long as we have each other,
我们就不是寂寞的
we're never truly alone.
你说的那些话真不错
That was cool. What you said.
谢谢
Thank you.
你想不想...
Uh... would you like to, uh...
去喝杯咖啡
get a cup... a cup of coffee...?
好的
Okay.
哥先走一步了  废柴联盟
Later, losers!
事到如今
然后我去了剑桥  超美妙的时光
So then I went to Cambridge, which was wonderful
不只是因为那是名校
not only because it's a good school
是因为那里看起来超像霍格沃茨的呢
but because it totally looks like Hogwarts.
小说《哈利波特》中  主角们就读的学校
我就是在那里爱上了天文学
That's where I fell in love with astronomy,
我现在是任职于加州理工的天体物理学家
and now I'm an astrophysicist at Caltech,
所以也可以这么说...
so I guess you could say, uh,
拉杰是我名  星辰是我命
Raj is my name and stars are my game.
我还有押韵命哦
And rhyming is also my game.
可以算是"一杰两命"
So, uh, two games.
好啦  我自己的事情说够了
Uh, anyway, that-that's enough about me.
我想听听关于你的一切
I want to hear everything about you.
我要去一趟厕所
I have to go to the bathroom.
我也会去厕所
I go to the bathroom, too.
虽然有时候频繁到我都不好意思说了
Sometimes more frequently than I care to admit.
不过我给医生检查过了  一切正常
Oh, I've had it checked out, it's nothing.
也太顺利了吧
This is going great!
能帮我的印度茶续杯吗
Can I have a refill on my chai tea?
太好了
Yes...
感觉就十分有戏啊
I have a good feeling about this.
早知道就买好套套了
I should have bought condoms.
生活大爆炸 第六季  第十七集
您好  我是谢尔顿·库珀博士
Hello, I'm Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
欢迎收看由谢尔顿·库珀出品的《有趣的旗帜》
Welcome to Sheldon Cooper Presents: Fun with Flags.
在此对本集节目的延误出品致歉
My apologies that this episode is coming late.
上周我曾拍摄了"黑人历史月"纪念集
I did shoot one last week, in honor of Black History Month,
但后来受到我室友的提点
but I was informed by my roommate
我在节目中对乔治·华盛顿·卡弗的精湛描述
that my spot-on portrayal of George Washington Carver
乔治·华盛顿·卡弗  黑人  美国教育家  植物学家
农业化学家  对美国农业有巨大贡献
会有人觉得带有"严重种族歧视"
could be considered "wildly racist."
我的心一直与所有的
My heart goes out to the members
非裔美国人群体同在
of the African-American community,
我们都是受所谓"高层"压迫的苦命人
who, like me, have been kept down by The Man.
《有趣的旗帜》不只是给旗帜狂热爱好者看的
Now, Fun with Flags is not just for the flag aficionado;
也十分适合新晋旗帜迷
it's also for the flag novice,
因此请了位特别嘉宾
so, to help me with that,
大家欢迎我的朋友  邻居  旗帜界处女
please welcome my friend, neighbor, and flag virgin--
不是现实生活的处女
yeah, not a real virgin.
她有过多次交媾经验了
She's had coitus many times.
有时就在本人听得见的范围里交媾呢
Sometimes within earshot of this flag enthusiast.
有次还是在本人在看《超人特工队》的时候
Once while he was trying to watch The Incredibles.
佩妮
Penny.
你好啊
Hello.
佩妮  我知道
So, Penny, I understand
你对旗帜有相当浓厚的兴趣  对吗
you would like to learn more about flags.
对啊  我有过太多次
Yeah, I can't tell you how many times
参加派对时  别人在大聊特聊旗帜
I've been at a party where everyone's talking about flags
而我却完全插不上话的经验了
and I just couldn't join in. Yeah.
那你来这里就对啦
Well, you came to the right place.
抱歉  我们能暂停一下下嘛
Uh, I'm sorry, can we just pause for a minute?
怎么了
What's wrong?
我只是觉得如果你对着我说话
I just think it might look more natural
会比你对着摄影机说话更自然
if you talked to me instead of the camera,
这样看起来更像在轻松聊天
you know, like, like a real conversation.
我们在表演课上有教过这个
It's something we work on in my acting class.
有意思
Interesting.
有些人在评语栏就有留言过
A few people in the comments section have said
说我的教学像机器人
that my delivery is robotic.
我一直以为是在称赞我
Perhaps that isn't the compliment it sounds like.
我们再试一遍吧  这一次
Yeah, let's try it again, and maybe, this time,
也多注意一下你的肢体语言
you could work on your body language a bit.
当你这样弯腰驼背
You know, when you're all hunched like that,
会像是拒观众于千里之外
you're shutting the audience out,
如果你放松  肢体张开
but when you're relaxed and open,
会像是欢迎大家进入
you're inviting them in.
有道理
Right.
那我该用哪一种呢
And which one do I want?
欢迎大家那种啊
Let's try open.
我们的好友  旗帜  教过我的一件事就是
If our friend, the flag, has taught me anything,
向着风指引你的方向飘
it's to go where the wind takes you.
不过要先确保自身良好地固定在旗杆上
As long as you remain firmly attached to a rigid pole.
开始
And... action.
佩妮
So, Penny...
哪些对旗帜的疑问会让你夜不成寐呢
what sort of flag questions keep you awake at night?
我是内布拉斯加州人
Um, well, I'm from Nebraska.
不如你给我讲讲我们的州旗
So what can you tell me about the state flag?
天啊  佩妮
Gosh, Penny...
你今早早餐吃了啥啊
what'd you have for breakfast?
喝了一杯"超棒问题果汁"吗
A big glass of good question juice?
内布拉斯加州的州旗面就只是州徽
The Nebraska state flag is simply the state seal
印在蓝底上
on a field of blue.
打开腿  欢迎大家进来
Spread your legs; invite them in.
相信我  绝对不对劲
I'm telling you, something's wrong.
拉杰碰到麻烦的时候  我都会有感应
I can always feel it when Raj is in trouble.
天啊  我们结婚前  你们俩是有多亲密啊
Geez, how close were you guys before we got married?
不要知道比较好
Don't look under that rock.
-拉杰  你没事吧  -你在家吗
- Raj, you okay? - You in there?
走开啦
Go away!
兄弟  开门嘛
Come on, buddy, open up.
我们都很担心你
We're worried about you.
就因为我没去上班
Oh, just because I stopped going to work
然后又不接电话  你们就觉得我出事了吗
and answering my phone you think something bad happened?
也可能是发生了好事啊
Maybe something good happened.
那有好事发生了吗
Did something good happen?
当然没有
Of course not!
好事从不发生在我身上
Nothing good ever happens!
怎么
What?
没事  就是感叹下
Nope, just-just... whoa.
里面一股恶臭味
It smells pretty ripe in here.
光是用眼睛都可以感觉到
You kind feel it in your eyes.
拉杰  发生什么事了
Raj, what's going on?
我又被一个女人羞辱了
I was humiliated by yet another woman.
你没有杀死她  然后碎尸吧
You didn't kill her and chop her up--
屋里的味道不是尸臭  对吧
that's not what we're smelling, right?
不是
No.
我带她去喝咖啡
I took her for coffee,
结果她为了摆脱我
and she snuck out the bathroom window
从厕所的窗户溜走了
to get away from me.
可怜的小宝贝
Oh, you poor baby.
我去看了
I went and looked.
那个窗户又高又小
It was a high and tiny window.
她一定是想逃到了极点
She must have been very motivated.
我很遗憾  那太伤人了  但拜托
I'm sorry. That's awful, but come on.
你得放下这件事
you got to shake it off.
对啊  你不能窝在公寓里
Yeah, you can't stay in your apartment
就此度过余生吧
for the rest of your life.
为什么不能
Why not?
有网上购物和隔天送达
With online shopping and overnight delivery,
我要什么有什么
I can get anything I want.
瞧
Look,
我刚在亚马逊上订了一箱炖牛肉罐头
I just ordered a case of Dinty Moore beef stew
和两只活龙虾
and two live lobsters on Amazon.
龙虾隔天就能送来
Lobsters overnight?
开什么玩笑  我看看
Oh, you're kidding. Let me see.
我也要
Well, I'll be.
还能再订个牛排
Look, you can throw in a couple steaks
配上一份海鲜牛排
and have a surf and turf.
海鲜牛排听起来不错
The surf and turf sounds good.
看看有没有玉米棒
See if they corn on the cob.
死阿宅们
Guys!
我们是来把他救出火坑
We're trying to get him out of here,
而不是把你俩推进去
not you in.
你们这是在浪费时间
You're wasting your time.
拜托  不要管我啦
Just please, leave me alone.
现在怎么办
Now what?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们可以去龙虾餐厅  边吃边谈啊
We could go to Red Lobster and talk about it.
谁不对龙虾有兴趣
We're all thinking it.
只不过我能礼貌地等他走了再谈
I just had the decency to wait for him to leave.
你好  谢尔顿
Hello, Sheldon.
你好
Hello.
"尼古丁成瘾"研究的
How's the final stage of
最后阶段进行得怎么样了
your nicotine addiction study going?
还行
Fine.
等下
Just hold on.
老娘在打电话呢
Mommy's on the phone!
抱歉
Sorry.
我们把猴子的香烟削减到一天一根
We've cut the monkeys down to one cigarette a day,
所以现在局面有点紧张
so things are a little intense.
让我不禁怀念大麻上瘾的扁形虫
Makes me miss my marijuana-abusing flatworms.
那些小家伙乖多了
Those guys were mellow.
好消息
Good news.
最新一集《有趣的旗帜》已经放到网上了
Uh, the latest episode of Fun with Flags is online.
好的  跟佩妮合作得怎么样
Oh, that's right. How'd it go with Penny?
比我期望的好多了
Much better than I expected.
她甚至给我一些关于表演
She even gave me some helpful tips
和肢体语言的有用建议
about acting and body language.
看着
Watch.
欢迎来到我的世界
Welcome to my world.
我的世界不欢迎你
Not welcome to my world.
欢迎
Welcome.
不欢迎
Not welcome.
意义隐晦  但力道十足
Subtle, but powerful.
我知道
I know.
我还在学习如何控制力道
I'm still learning to control it.
那你有跟佩妮说她的建议很有用吗
Did you tell Penny how helpful she was?
我为什么要说
Why would I do that?
因为她是你的朋友  她帮了你大忙
Because she's your friend, and she did a nice job.
听到你这么说  她肯定会开心
I'm sure she'd like to hear it.
好吧
All right.
我不是说现在啊  喂
I didn't mean now. Hello?
是  是  你想要香烟
Yeah, yeah, you want a cigarette.
我还想要个正常的男朋友呢
Well, I'd like a normal boyfriend.
自己忍着吧
Deal with it.
有事吗
Oh, hi. What's up?
需要我把门关上
You need me to shut the door
好让你像平时那样敲门吗
so you can do your knocking thing?
不用了
No.
-我还没开始  所以没关系  -那就好
- I didn't start yet; it's fine. - Okay.
那你找我干嘛
So, what do you need?
我在想
Well, I was thinking
你昨晚帮我的事
about you helping me out last night...
佩妮
Penny.
我是过来告诉你
And I just wanted to tell you...
佩妮
Penny.
关于"谁的表现很棒"
...that the answer to the question,
这个问题的答案  是你
"who did a great job?" is you.
佩妮
Penny.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? -Yes.
你在镜头面前表现得很自然
You were very natural in front of the camera,
而且我觉得你建议非常有用
and I found your suggestions extremely helpful.
亲爱的  你让我今天真开心
Aw, sweetie, you just made my day.
任务完成
Okay.
我的表演课在周五晚上有场演出
Hey, my acting class is putting on a play Friday night.
我可以把你和艾米放进宾客名单哦
I could put you and Amy on the guest list.
那听起来太无趣了
Oh, that sounds terrible.
我怎么可能想去啊
Why would I want to do that?
没错
That's right.
没有打火机  有烟也白搭
They're no good without the lighter.
你这表扬佩妮的建议可"真好"
Well, so much for your advice on complimenting Penny.
为什么  怎么了
Why? What happened?
她想绑我们去
She tried to rope us into going
她的表演课  看个话剧
to her acting class to see a play.
别担心
Don't worry.
本人高瞻远瞩
Luckily, I had the good sense
早把这想法扼杀于摇篮之中了
to drown that kitten in the river.
谢尔顿  你太失礼了
Sheldon, that's very rude.
她为你的节目出了力
She helped you with your show.
你应该好好报答她
The right thing to do is reciprocate
去看她的话剧
by going to see her play.
规矩也太多了吧
Oh, so many crazy rules.
你扔过来的最好是巧克力糖
That better be Tootsie Rolls you're throwing at me!
佩妮  佩妮
Penny. Penny.
佩妮
Penny.
感觉好多了
Oh yeah, much better.
干嘛
What?
艾米告诉我
Amy pointed out to me
你帮了我的忙
that since you did something nice for me,
所以我也应该礼尚往来
I'm obligated to do something nice for you.
所以
So...
好  我会去看你的傻帽话剧
yes, I'll go to your dopey play.
可我已经不想让你去了
Hey, I don't want you to go anymore.
为什么
Why not?
你如果愿意的话可以去
You should go 'cause you want to go,
但若是被强迫就算了
not because you have to.
老天爷啊  更多规矩  何时才能是尽头啊
Oh, Dear Lord, more rules? Where does it stop?
我能不能想去
Can I want to go
是因为我必须想去
because I have to want to go?
行  你想怎样就怎样
Okay. Do whatever you want.
不行  等等
Yeah, but now, wait.
我想怎样就怎样
Do whatever I want...
还是我必须想怎样就怎样
or whatever I have to want?
我的天  你来看话剧就是了
Oh, for God's sake, just come to the play.
好吧
All right.
我不想去  不过这决定挺有道理的
I don't want to, but at least that makes sense.
我好几天没见过拉杰了
You know, I haven't seen Raj in several days.
他还是我们的小团体中的一员吗
Is he no longer a part of our social group?
如果不是的话  我们要开始面试替补人员吗
And if so, should we be interviewing for a replacement?
或许这次我们该找个拉丁人
Perhaps, this time, we go Latin.
他决定再也不踏出自己的公寓了
He's just decided he's never leaving his apartment again.
真棒
Oh, brilliant.
我一直想这么做来着
I've been itching to pull that trigger.
他很伤心  因为总交不到女朋友
He's upset because he can't get anywhere with women.
要不要我去给他点建议
Would it help if I gave him some pointers?
我逗你们玩呢
I'm just funnin' ya.
你好
Hi.
不知道你还记不记得我
I don't know if you remember me,
那天晚上我来参加过你的聚会来着
but I was here the other night at your party.
对  你和拉杰一起走的
Oh, yeah, you left with Raj.
是的
Uh, yeah.
就是你吗
You're the one?
我告诉你
Okay, let me tell you something.
你甩掉的那个人
That guy you blew off
是我最好的朋友
happens to be my best friend.
他被伤透了心
Okay? He was devastated.
对不起
Sorry.
你能把这个给他吗
Can you just give him this?
好
Okay.
但我得警告你
But I gotta warn you,
拉杰是个骄傲  情感激烈的人
Raj is a proud, passionate man.
如果你再撇下他偷跑掉
If you go running out on him again,
你离成为过去式
you're only gonna get, like,
就剩三到四次机会了
three or four more chances before you are history.
别这样嘛  她回来了
Come on, she came back.
这是好消息
This is good news.
你应该好好庆祝才对
You should celebrate.
我不想庆祝
I don't want to celebrate.
一点也不吗
Not even a little?
我们可以办个裤子派对啊
I mean... we could have a pants party.
快去找条穿上
Go put some on.
我要她的电话号码做什么
Why would I want her number?
我不想和这女人再有任何瓜葛
I don't want anything to do with this woman.
-拜托  拉杰  -你不明白
- Oh, come on, Raj... - No, you don't get it.
我再也不想和任何女人有瓜葛了
I want nothing to do with any woman.
我心已死
My heart is stone.
从现在起  我要当个和尚
From now on, I'm a monk.
我要拒绝尘世一切享受
I renounce all worldly pleasures.
除了龙虾
Except for lobster.
还有蒜蓉酱
And garlic butter.
我本来想告诉你这是她的损失
Boy, I want to tell you it's her loss,
但你还真是让我说不出口啊
but you are not making it easy.
你真是个好朋友  这么帮我  但...
You're-you're a good friend for trying to help, but...
我意已决
I've made my choice.
好吧
All right.
-那回头见  -回见
- Well, I'll see you around. - See you.
等等  把她的号码拿走
Oh, wait-- take her number.
别留下诱惑
I don't want the temptation.
好
Okay.
我必须坚强起来  坚持自己的奋斗目标
I must be strong so I don't stray from my true purpose:
宇宙研究
the study of the universe.
好吧
All right.
谢谢你让我再也不想吃龙虾了
Thanks for ruining lobster for me.
等等
Wait!
把号码给我
Give me the number!
艾米  你的上瘾研究怎么样了
So, Amy, what's going on with your addiction study?
很遗憾  我已经被项目团队踢出来了
Sadly, I'm no longer associated with that project.
为什么  出什么事了
Why? What happened?
典型的狗屁官僚主义
Typical bureaucratic nonsense.
你可以让动物对有害物质上瘾
You can get animals addicted to a harmful substance,
可以解剖它们的大脑
you can dissect their brains,
但你向它们扔它们自己的排泄物
but you throw their own feces back at them
就突然之间"不专业"了
and suddenly you're "unprofessional."
真是抱歉
I'm sorry...
我真多嘴...
...that I asked.
好啦  白痴话剧早看早完
All right, let's get this stupid play over with.
等等
Uh, hang on.
掏空你的口袋
Empty your pockets.
为什么
Why?
你知道原因
You know why.
任天堂游戏机
The Nintendo DS.
索尼游戏机
And the PSP.
还有一台呢
Now the Gameboy.
让不让人活了
Aw, for Pete's sake.
现在可以走了吗
Can we go now?
全部交出来了吗
Well, is that all of it?
放下就好
Just set it down.
告诉你  这可不是白痴话剧
Just so you know, this is not a stupid play.
《欲望号街车》是美国经典
A Streetcar Named Desire is an American classic.
原来是讲地面电车啊
It's about streetcars?
太好了  那这个也不要了
Oh, great. I won't need this.
等下
Just a sec.
谁会说"等下"啊
Oh, who says "just a sec"?
我恨我自己
I hate myself!
你好
Hello.
Hi.
要进来吗
Uh, would you like to come in?
不用了  我马上就走
Oh, no, I can't stay.
我只是想说
I just wanted to say...
抱歉我从咖啡店逃走了
I'm sorry for running out of the coffee shop.
那样做太不像话了
That wasn't cool.
所以
So, uh...
是的
Yeah.
对不起
I'm sorry.
等等
Wait.
至少能告诉我  哪里出错了吗
Can you at least tell me what went wrong?
没事的  什么原因我都能接受
It's okay. I can take anything.
除非是说我做的事
Unless it's something I did,
说的话  或是我这人怎样
or said, or am.
这些原因会让我发火的
'Cause those are, like, my buttons.
不是这些原因
No, it's not any of that.
只是
It's just...
我在陌生人周围
I kind of have a hard time
会感觉非常不自在
around people I don't know.
真的吗
Really?
那你那晚
Then what were you doing
为什么会去漫画店
at the comic book store that night?
我在尝试强迫自己
I've been trying to force myself into situations
面对我不喜欢的环境
that I'm not comfortable with.
我在商店橱窗上看到宣传单
I saw the flyer in the store window,
我强迫自己去的
and I made myself go in.
我压根连个漫画粉都不是
I don't even like comic books.
我也不喜欢
Yeah, me neither.
那你为什么要去
Then what were you doing there?
我说谎了  我爱漫画书
I lied. I love them.
我这样说只是希望你愿意和我约会
I only said that so you'd go out with me.
你还是不要和我约会为妙
Oh, you don't want to do that.
我不能算是个正常人
I'm kind of broken.
太好了
That's great.
我也不正常
I'm broken, too.
你不是的
Oh, no, you're not.
我相当不正常
Oh, I totally am.
如果不是因为这瓶啤酒
If it wasn't for this beer,
我现在都没办法和你讲话
I couldn't even talk to you right now.
我完全就是一残疾货
I'm a wreck.
我有很多非常严重的毛病
There are many things seriously wrong with me.
而且不是指怪癖哦
And not quirks, either.
准确来说是可诊断的心理问题
Like... diagnosable psychological problems.
有可能是脑子坏了
Maybe brain damage.
我怎么知道你不是随便说说的
Well, how do I know you're not just saying that?
和我约会一次
Go out with me on one date,
我向你保证  你会看见满是毛病的我
and I promise you, you'll see.
好的
Okay.
发短信给我
Text me.
拜
Bye.
你不会后悔的
You won't regret it.
我是你这辈子所碰到  最悲催的男人
I'm the most pathetic guy you've ever met.
就这样  孩子们
And that, boys and girls...
泡妞就是这样的
is how it's done.
你非常爱她  对吗
You love her very much, don't you?
是的
Yes.
我觉得你是个非常有奉献精神的人
I think you have a great capacity for devotion.
她去世后你会孤单对吗
You'll be lonely when she passes on, won't you?
我明白这种感觉
I understand what that is.
孤单的感觉吗
To be lonely?
她很不错啊
She's pretty good, huh?
的确
She is.
什么时候才能演到有轨电车啊
But when do they get to the part about streetcars?
在我很小的时候
...when I was a very young girl.
我16岁时  发现了
When I was 16 years old, I made the discovery...
爱情
love.
一下子
All at once,
一切来得太突然了
and much, much too completely.
就好像你突然将明亮的灯光
It was like you suddenly turned a blinding light
照到总是一半处于黑暗中的东西一样
on something that had always been half a shadow.
于是我的生活发生了天翻地覆的变化
That's how it struck the world for me.
但我是不幸的
But I was unlucky.
被欺骗了
Deluded.
她的表演太精彩了
She's remarkable.
的确
She really is.
咱们的佩妮是大明星
Our Penny's a star.
她怎么能记住那么多台词
How can she remember all those lines,
但作为服务员  却不记得
but as a waitress, she can't remember
我的汉堡是不要加番茄的
"no tomato" on my hamburger?